BENINU PANDIAN

Cell: 9791788158 • beninupandian@gmail.com

JAVA SOFTWARE DEVELOPER CUM PRODUCTION SUPPORT

Sun Certified Java Developer, Certified SAFe Practitioner with a passion for software development especially with agile practices, with an in depth knowledge of OOP and Design Patterns.

Over 9 years of software development experience in JAVA and microservices including high transactional enterprise applications, with team leadership and mentoring experience.

Has the ability to understand and transform complex business requirements into software, ensuring applications are delivered on time, to specification, are scalable, performance optimized and maintainable.

A highly motivated individual who is always learning, able to work to tight deadlines, and who can communicate effectively with technical peers as well as business users. Someone who encourages learning and the sharing of ideas and is always open to new ways of working.

Key Skills

Core Programming Languages:

Java, J2EE, Microservices – Spring Boot, Shell Script, Node Js

Databases:

ORACLE 11g

CMS:

Magnolia CMS

Development Methodologies:

Scaled Agile

Tools and Technologies:

Eclipse, IntelliJ, Jboss, Webservices, Spring webflow, Maven, Jenkins, Jira, Mercurial, Git, Grafana, Icinga

Certificates

- SCJP
- SAFe 4 Practitioner

Valid Work Permit

Till Feb 2020

FINLAND

Professional Experience

ROYALTY CALCULATION ENGINE

August 2019 - Current

The royalty calculation engine is an event based system which handles royalty calculations for customers. The system handles customers with varying contracts which define their royalty terms.

The systems consists of individual services which are co-ordinated by an orchestration engine. The services react on receiving different types of events.

Key Technologies: Java, REST, Spring, SQS/SNS

TELECOM CUSTOMER SUPPORT SALES CHANNELS

September 2012 – Current

The sales channels include a collection of systems that interact with customers, dealers and Customer support representatives. The systems are part of an enterprise application that helps with customer 360° view, order capturing, and service assurance. SAFe Development methodology is followed for development. The applications consists of the below parts.

- Frontend
 - Frontend system consists of business logic for order capturing.
 - Handling Service assurance.
 - 360° view for a customer
- Middleware
 - Consist of SOAP and REST services.
 - Collates data from various downstream systems on request from frontend applications.
- Order Processing Tool
 - Processing and partial-provisioning of order placed through Channels.

Key Technologies: JAVA, JBOSS, Oracle, Web Services, Spring webflow, SAFe Agile, Jenkins, Jira, GIT, Mercurial, Maven, IntelliJ, Eclipse, Magnolia CMS

BROADBAND PROVISIONING SYSTEM

December 2010 - August 2012

The Broadband provisioning system is a multi-server, multi-process, and highly parallel system that provisions broadband orders of a leading UK Telecom company. Based on SOA, It uses Web services for receiving orders and using sendmail, it notifies customers on their order status. It manages Broadband order details and product details. Agile development process is used for development activities. It includes a Hub which based on webservice request, collects data from subsystems and sends response.

- Implemented server side changes for preventing DOS attacks.
- Developed component to get Engineer notes for the Customer Portal through webservice.
- Performed VDC Migration on the complete system, reverse engineering for old applications
- Developed a number of cronjobs for timely execution of tasks to avoid performance issues.
- Placed scripts to identify server status and notify through mail in case of server issues.
- Analyze issues and provide feasible solution.

Key Technologies: JAVA, XML, BMC Remedy, Oracle, Web Services, Spring, Agile

Work Experience

Amazon India- Aug 2019 till date

Tata Consultancy Services – Dec 2020 to Aug 2019

Education

KARUNYA UNIVERSITY – COIMBATORE

Bachelor Degree in Information Technology, 2010

4 year curriculum focusing on application development, networks, algorithms and software architecture design

Languages

- English fluent verbal and writing skills
- Tamil fluent verbal and writing skills

References

References are available upon request